本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  CiciXT
・ 翻译  麦结
■
・ 翻译  紫玉
・ 翻译  卫老哥
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  茶炒栗子
・ 翻译  艾瑞卡
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  宅女之后
译  somehacker
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  凭陵新月  Sage  兜兜爹  阿包  凭陵新月  Sage  兜兜爹  阿包  凭陵新月  Sage  兜兜爹
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
If your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季第二十集
突发新闻 泄露的情报预算
泄露的情报预算披露
The leaked black budget report reveals
突发新闻 泄露的情报预算
秘密军事情报行动组织
several classified military intelligence programs,
突发新闻 泄露的情报预算
旧金山论坛报
国防部情报预算泄露
突发新闻 泄露的情报预算
旧金山论坛报
国防部情报预算泄露
华盛顿先驱报
突发新闻 泄露的情报预算
旧金山论坛报
国防部情报预算泄露
数十项秘密行动组织泄露
如"白垩鹰"组织  "牵玫瑰"组织
with code names like Chalk Eagle and Tractor Rose.
数十项秘密行动组织泄露
其中一个"北极光"组织
A program designated Northern Lights has...
"北极光"组织的预算远超
Northern Lights has a budget far outstripping
突发新闻
秘密政府组织曝光
其他组织
any other program.
被归为是"反恐活动资金"
Classified as "Operation support for counterterrorism activities,"
具体情况不明
The details are scarce.
有人怀疑其涉嫌
Some have speculated that it may be related
监控美国公民
to the surveillance of American citizens.
这  对我们的隐私意味着什么呢
If so, what does that mean for our privacy?
媒体拿到组织的名字了
Media got a hold of the program name,
说明你的老上司主控者下台了
which means your old boss Control just lost it.
那贱人想杀我
Bitch tried to kill me.
乐得见她任人鱼肉
Nice to see her head on the chopping block for change.
所有跟机器有关的人
Anyone connected to the machine will be
都会将证据深埋地下
burying evidence 6 feet down.
组织可能会有危险
Could put the program in jeopardy.
政府又封不住机器
Government can't put the machine back in the box.
我们仍然收着号码
We're still getting our numbers,
说明开着机呢
So the lights are on.
走吧
Let's go.
早
Morning.
你们尝了那煎饼没
You guys have the pancakes?
试试香蕉巧克力碎的  妙不可言
Try the banana chocolate chip--amazing.
什么
What?
不先寒暄下
No small talk?
好吧  我无所谓
All right, fine by me.
货拿了
You have the product?
你瞧呢
What's it look like?
钱拿了
You got the money?
一百万  成交吧
1 million. We have a deal?
成交
You got it, man.
这么快
That fast, huh?
等不到回了酒店再算账吗
Couldn't even wait to get back to the hotel to count it?
你看  雷  你同伴已经在夏威夷选好豪宅了
See, Ray, your partner's already picked out a house in Hawaii.
你一转身
So as soon as you turn your back,
他就要往你脑袋上来两枪
he's gonna put two in your head
自己吞下所有钱了
and keep all the money for himself.
不过你猜怎么着  胡里奥
But guess what, Julio.
雷已经付了一艘游艇的订金
Ray here put a down payment on a yacht,
告诉你的妞儿要带她环游世界了
told your girl he'd show her the world.
五十万挺多的  不过一百万
500,000 buys a lot. But a million?
你们俩都不惜干掉对方了
Both of you would take out your partner for that.
你这个贱人
You little son of a...
抱歉了两位  生意黄了
Sorry, guys. Deal's off.
好梦吧  小子们
Sweet dreams, boys.
交给弗斯科了
Fusco can clean this up.
坐二十年牢能保证他们无法自相残杀了
20 years in lockup ought to keep 'em from killing each other.
看  一切照旧
See? Business as usual.
政府那边的组织被冻结
Even if the government's program's on ice,
机器也照吐号码不误
the machine is still spitting out numbers.
以芬奇的性子
You know Finch.
就算没有北极光  他的机器也会想法子
Even without Northern Lights, his machine will find a way
保护国家安全
to maintain national security.
真的吗
Really?
那谁负责相关威胁
Then who's handling the relevant threats?
根
Root.
孩子们
Hey, kids.
贩毒时想我了
You miss me between drug deals?
是啊  拿你当我肠子里的蛔虫那么想
Yeah. I miss you like I miss an intestinal parasite.
我喜欢你的比喻
I love your similes.
上来吧  肖
Hop on, Shaw.
阿拉斯加有个相关号码
We've got a relevant number in Alaska.
我们得偷架飞机
We're gonna steal a jet.
听着挺好玩儿
Does sound kind of fun.
给我寄明信片
Send me a postcard.
别闷闷不乐了  阴郁男
Turn that frown upside down, Lurch.
卢尔希为《亚当斯一家》经典角色  笑点请观其剧照
你也要去度假了
You're going on vacation too.
哈罗德马上要从华盛顿特区给你电话了
Harold's about to call from D.C.
他需要你的帮助
He needs your help.
里瑟先生  恐怕我们的业务
Mr. Reese, I'm afraid our services
要扩展到首都了
are required in the nation's capital.
听说了  这就去
I heard. On my way.
纽约
华盛顿特区
芬奇
Finch?
还行啊
This'll work.
太好了  你来了
Oh, good, you're here.
抱歉  在图书馆耽搁了一会儿
Sorry, got tied up at the library.
很高兴你准备好了长期出差
I'm happy to see that you've come prepared for a long haul.
我能不能奢望里边装了武器之外的东西
Dare I hope that you've packed something other than weaponry?
还带了门外设陷阱用的地雷拉发线
There's some trip wire to booby-trap the room door,
以及牙刷
and a toothbrush.
口腔卫生是蛮重要
Oral hygiene is something, I suppose.
你收到了华盛顿的号码
You got a number here in D.C.?
看来是的
It would seem so.
对时刻警惕的调查
My investigation into vigilance's activities
只好先暂停
will have to wait.
现在根在收相关号码了
Root is getting the relevant numbers now.
肖跟她在一起
Shaw is with her.
我们进入了一个新领域
We're entering uncharted territory,
既要负责相关号码  又要负责无关号码
tasked with both relevant and irrelevant numbers.
战线拉太长了  芬奇
Already stretched pretty thin, Finch.
还是在最糟糕的时机
And at the worst possible time.
德西玛正要将"撒马利亚人"上线
Just when Decima is determined to make Samaritan operational.
也许这时机不是巧合
Maybe the timing's not a coincidence.
恐怕是有联系
I fear that it may be connected.
如今形势古怪
These are strange times,
"撒马利亚人"的威胁不容低估
and the threat of Samaritan should not be underestimated.
你怎么知道它现在还没开始运作
How do you know it's not already up and running?
因为我们还没死  里瑟先生
Because we'd be dead, Mr. Reese.
机器是盾  保护生命
The machine is a Shield. It protects lives.
我设计确保它不会
I designed it with safeguards to prevent it
被滥用来毁灭世界
being abused as an agent of destruction.
"撒马利亚人"是开放系统  是剑
Samaritan is an open system, a sword.
一旦它获取了政府信号权限
If it gains access to the government's feeds,
其力量将无可限量
there will be no checks on its power.
无法阻止其信息
There will be no limits to the knowledge possessed
被私人控制
by the person controlling it.
德西玛一定会用来攻击其敌人
Decima would definitely use it to hunt down its enemies.
身为机器的最知情者
And as confidants of the machine,
你我将会首当其冲
you and I would be at the top of the list.
也许机器是想保护我们
So maybe the machine is trying to protect us.
不  我造它是为了保护所有人
No, I built it to protect everyone,
一个一个来
One number at a time.
天啊
Oh, my.
怎么了
What?
这是罗杰・麦考特
That's Roger McCourt.
新号码是美国国会议员
Our new number is a United States Congressman?
来自伊利诺斯州
From Illinois.
在国会任职六届
Six terms in Congress.
目前是众议院规则委员会的少数党成员
Current ranking minority member of the pivotal House Rules Committee.
幕后男人  罗杰・麦考特
众议院规则委员会主席欢迎罗杰・麦考特
规则委员会负责法案的走向
The Rules Committee controls the flow of legislation--
加速通过或是彻底叫停
spurring it forward or stopping it altogether.
他有这么大的权力
If he has that much power,
肯定树敌不少
he'll have plenty of enemies.
鉴于"时刻警惕"最近在华盛顿的活动
Given their activities in Washington recently,
他们颇有嫌疑
Vigilance would have to be a suspect.
不过  麦考特一直公开反对政府监控
However, McCourt's been an outspoken opponent of government surveillance.
华盛顿先驱报
麦考特倡议国会反对政府监控
会不会是德西玛想要他命
Could Decima want him dead?
有可能
Perhaps.
不过谋杀国会议员这种手段过于高调  不像他们
But killing a congressman would seem too flashy for them.
这年头  没人喜欢政府
Nobody likes the government these days.
任何心怀不满的公民都有可能变成刺客
Any disgruntled citizen could be the assassin.
我们得去国会大厦
We have to get to the Capitol.
你这叫音乐么
You call this music?
芬奇  你还好吗
Finch? Are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
咱们放过那只悲惨的猫咪行不
Can we put the screeching cat out of its misery?
这不是《猫》  是威尔第
It's not Feline. It's Verdi.
歌剧《茶花女》的作曲家  意大利浪漫主义作曲大师
他的《游吟诗人》
There's a performance of Il Trovatore
正在肯尼迪中心上演  我想去看
at the Kennedy Center that I'd like to catch.
下次让你当DJ
Next time you can be the disc jockey.
你喜欢什么  我们就听什么
We'll listen to whatever you like.
那不如下次我唱歌给你听
Maybe next time I'll just sing for you.
我唱《指环》可拿手了
I do a great Ring Cycle, you know.
德国后浪漫主义大师理查德・瓦格纳作品  故事内涵  建议百度
我才不要听你唱[女武神]伯伦希尔
I think I'll skip your Brunnhilde.
随你高兴
Suit yourself.
似乎这位议员的危险
Looks like our congressman is in danger
是被说客烦死
of catching lobbyist disease.
很难监听麦考特
It's gonna be difficult to get ears on McCourt.
他的助手负责全部电话
His aide handles all phone activity.
麦考特不想政府监听自己吗
McCourt doesn't want the government eavesdropping on him?
议员比谁都清楚
Congressmen know better than anyone
上司可能在听
that their employer could be listening.
我们得靠近他
We'll have to get close to him,
筛选可能的威胁
narrow down the list of threats.
国会警察保镖不会让人靠近他
The Capitol Police detail won't let anyone near him.
议员如果要特勤局保护
Congressmen are eligible for Secret Service protection
就必须存在额外风险
in the event of additional risk.
还没人企图杀他
No one's made an attempt on his life yet.
议员不知道自己有危险
The congressman doesn't even know the danger he's in.
现在知道了  开车  芬奇
He knows now. Drive, Finch.
我得告诉你  里瑟先生
I have to tell you, Mr. Reese,
我不赞同这一策略
I don't approve of this strategy.
是你自己说的  你做的假身份
You're the one who said you couldn't make an alias
通不过特勤局的审查
that would pass Secret Service muster.
我是说时间不够
I said I didn't have time.
我当时可不知道你会去偷
I didn't know you were gonna steal the identity
真特勤局特工的身份
of an actual Secret Service agent.
借用下罢了  放松
I'm just borrowing it. Relax.
叫点客房服务吧
Order some room service.
要我放松  你先告诉我  你怎么处理
Perhaps I will when you tell me what you've done
那位真阿伯特特工了
with the real Agent Abbott.
他在机场附近的旅馆里舒服地休息呢
He's resting comfortably in a motel room near the airport.
怎么个"舒服"
Define "comfortably."
不聊了  芬奇
Gotta go, Finch.
规则委员会的会议是十分钟后
The Rules Committee is meeting in ten minutes,
杂志采访在十一点半
you have your journal interview at 11:30,
午餐在海鲜烤坊
and then lunch at ocean grill
与"隐私保护"的辛西娅・卡罗尔
with Cynthia Carol from Privacy First
讨论您提出的反监控倡议
to discuss your anti-surveillance initiative.
-早上好  莱斯丽  -早上好  议员先生
- Good morning, Leslie. - Good morning, congressman.
这是谁
Who's this?
这位是阿伯特特工  特勤局的
This is agent Abbott, Secret Service.
他被派来保护您
He's been assigned to you.
因为枪击
Because of the shooting?
抱歉  我今天一直在考虑
Oh, sorry, I was thinking more
自己将要做的事情
about the business ahead of me today
而不是过去的事情
rather than behind.
你是哪里人  阿伯特
Where you from, Abbott?
他来自俄克拉荷马州塔尔萨
He's from Tulsa, Oklahoma.
塔尔萨  先生
Tulsa, sir.
塔尔萨  俄克拉荷马州  好人  社会中坚
Tulsa, Oklahoma. Good people, salt of the earth.
还有今晚  肯尼迪中心威尔第歌剧的票
And for tonight, tickets to the Verdi opera at the Kennedy Center.
我非得去吗
Do I have to go to this?
跟猫咪惨叫似的
This sounds like screeching cats.
您答应过妻子了
You promised your wife.
我可以开枪打你的腿  先生
I could shoot you in the leg, sir.
什么
Pardon me?
可以救你解脱歌剧之苦
Might get you out of the opera.
这位杜兰  特别想加入特勤局
You know, Duran here, he always wanted to be Secret Service.
是吗  杜兰
Isn't that right, Duran?
有阵子是  先生
At one time, sir.
你对阿伯特好点儿
If you show Abbott some love here,
没准儿他能替你美言几句
Maybe he'll put in a good word for you.
咱们今天可以无视交通信号灯了  是吧
And we can dispense with the stoplights today, okay?
-麦考特  -邓非
- McCourt! - Dunphy.
你应该先打个电话
You should've called first.
我办公室今早没人
My office is slammed this morning.
是航空公司合同的事吗
Is this about the airline contract?
他们在仗势欺人  麦克
They're trying to stick it to us, Mac.
我听说你要支持他们
And now I'm hearing you might be taking their side
不支持工会了
instead of the Union's?
邓非  邓非
Dunphy, Dunphy.
应该是布鲁斯・邓非
It must be Bruce Dunphy,
伊利诺伊机师工会领导
Part of the leadership of the Illinois Machinists Union.
合同是不怎么样
I know it's a lousy contract,
不过  我想你还是签了好
but I do think that you ought to sign it.
真不敢相信  你个背后捅刀子的贱
Unbelievable. You backstabbing son of a--
等等  等等
Whoa, hold it, hold it.
你以为你可以占便宜就算  甩了我们
You think you can pull this bait and switch with us,
甩了我  拍屁股走人吗
with me, and get away with it?
看来麦考特惹到不该惹的工会头子了
Looks like McCourt might have crossed the wrong Union boss.
条件是差了点  但总算能让工厂维持下去
It's not a good deal, but it does keep the plant open.
而且你可以更有力地竞争
And it puts you at the front of the line
更大的政府合同
for a bigger government contract
就在明年
that's coming down the pike next year.
-另一份合同  -没错
- Another contract? - Yeah.
你看  布鲁斯  我照应着你们呢
So you see, Bruce, I am looking out for your guys.
但你得信任我
But you do have to trust me.
我有点太性急了
I guess I jumped the gun a little bit.
没事
Forget it.
你妻子也和你一起来了吗
Is your wife in town with you?
-是的  -给
- Yeah. - Here.
我请客
Go as my guest.
很经典  她会喜欢的
It's classical stuff. She'll love it.
真的吗  谢啦  麦克
Really? Oh, thanks, Mac.
我的荣幸
It's my pleasure.
让你的人别担心
Tell your guys not to worry.
记住  我是你们的人
Remember, I'm your man.
谢谢
Thanks.
莱斯丽  打电话给我妻子
Leslie, will you call my wife
告诉她很不幸那歌剧票已售罄
and tell her unfortunately the opera was sold out?
看来这位国会议员游刃有余
It would appear our congressman has quite a knack
擅长摆脱不利局面
for getting himself out of unpleasant situations.
是啊  那歌剧太凶残了
Yeah, that opera would've been brutal.
我通常可不会任人招之即来
I'm not accustomed to taking meetings on such short notice,
但你声名远播
but your reputation precedes you.
别担心  参议员
Don't worry, Senator.
我一片诚意
I come with only the best of intentions.
需要我为你做什么
So what can I do for you?
其实是我为你和你的"北极光"问题做什么
Actually it's what I can do for you and your Northern Lights problem.
如果你是指情报预算报告泄露之事
If you're referring to the leaked black budget report,
我只是其中百余名字之一罢了
mine's just one of 100 names found in there.
我已经澄清过了  我一无所知
I've already made it clear I have no knowledge of that project.
是吗
Really?
我认为你知之甚多
I thought you knew a great deal about it,
尤其是2008年马沙文雅岛秘密会议之后
especially since the 2008 policy retreat on Martha's Vineyard
你从那时起开始领导这一项目
when you were tapped to shepherd the program.
你不会认为
Surely you didn't think,
在这个你监视所有人的世界里
in a world where you were surveilling everyone,
没人监视你吧
that no one was watching you.
那
So...
你想做什么
what is it you want?
我告诉过你了
As I told you,
帮忙
to help.
向媒体泄露情报预算的组织
The group responsible for leaking your black budget to the press
自称为"时刻警惕"
calls themselves Vigilance.
隐私恐怖分子
Privacy terrorists.
这是他们的领导者之一
This is one of their leaders,
化名叫彼得・科利尔
known by his alias as Peter Collier.
真是讽刺
Ironic.
你冒着仕途被毁的风险
You risked your career
隐藏那个保护国家的项目
hiding a program designed to protect the country,
它却无法在你需要时保护你免受"时刻警惕"的伤害
yet it couldn't protect you from this group when you needed it to.
你现在不得不关闭它
And now you've had to shut it down...
让你的国家毫无保护
leaving your country unprotected.
细思恐极
A frightening prospect indeed.
国家总会受到保护
The country will always be protected.
是的  我肯定你在考虑替代方法
Yes, I'm sure you're weighing alternative approaches,
正如贵总统所言
as your president might say.
我可以帮你省点时间
I can save you the time.
我的公司  德西玛科技
My company, Decima Technologies,
马上就能完成一个新监视系统的开发
is finalizing development of a new surveillance system.
恕我直言
All due respect,
我们也做过类似尝试  效果难说
we've gone down a similar path with mixed results.
北极光极有效
Northern Lights was effective
不过被其创造者的道德观影响了
but compromised by the ethics of its creator.
只发号施令  不接受指令
It spoke but never listened.
而我的  能接受指令  遵守指令
What I have not only listens but obeys.
它能找出任何人  随时随地
It can find anyone anywhere anytime.
你开口一问就行
You merely need to ask.
虽然听上去不错
As intriguing as that sounds,
但国会里有些人
there are some members of congress
正就这次的丑闻大做文章
making too much hay out of this latest scandal
不会再批准另外的项目
to ever green-light another program.
跟你的同事们聊聊我的提议
Share my proposal with your colleagues.
只要感兴趣
If there is interest...
反对声不是问题
dissenting voices will not be a problem.
你怎么能肯定
How can you be sure?
因为  参议员
Because, Senator,
有阻碍存在
obstacles are only obstacles
只要移去就好
until you move them out of the way.
你跟着议员多久了
So how long you been with the congressman?
久到知道他不需要特勤局保护
Long enough to know he doesn't need Secret Service protection.
那枪击是怎么回事
What about the shooting?
只是些反政府激进分子
Just some antigovernment wing nut
想上新闻罢了
looking to make the news cycle.
也有可能
I suppose that's possible.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
是我主管  总是缠着我不放
That's my supervisor. Guy's always in my ear.
查到什么了  芬奇
What do you got, Finch?
什么也没有
Nothing of note.
麦考特根本没有敌人
McCourt's list of enemies is practically nonexistent.
他竞选过程出奇干净
He ran a surprisingly clean campaign to get into office,
他目前反对非法监控的态度
and his current stand against unchecked surveillance
让他在两党都受到青睐
has endeared him to elements of both parties.
那他的私生活呢
What about his personal life?
没问题  经济宽裕  没有债务
No red flags--finances are sound, carries no debt,
持有的股票也令人赞叹
and has an impressive stock portfolio.
有什么能帮你的吗  朋友
Help you with something, friend?
放开我
Let go of me.
我努力客气了
I'm trying to be polite here.
没事的  阿伯特  我来处理
It's all right, Abbott, I've got this.
请坐
Have a seat.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
当地的流浪者  我经常看见他
Local homeless guy. I've seen him around.
麦考特认识他
McCourt knows him?
不  但那种人都认识麦考特
No, but people like him know McCourt.
他经常请有需要的人用餐
He's got a standing offer to buy a meal for anyone who needs one.
这是他去年开始的一项实践
It's a practice he started last year
旨在唤起对流浪者的关注
to raise awareness for the homeless problem.
再来一张  议员
One more, Congressman.
同时帮他提升公众形象
It also helps burnish his public image.
-好了  -给他上份汤
- Okay. - Get him some soup.
芬奇  记下来
Finch, take this down.
E5-9MI6
Echo five dash nine mike india six.
车牌吗
A license plate?
追踪它试试
See if you can trace it.
阿伯特  走了
Abbott, chop-chop!
怎么回事
What was that?
算了
Forget it.
我当初真该跟着根走
Starting to think I should've gone with Root.
华盛顿特区
迈阿密
谢谢你陪我完成这些活儿
Thanks for being my travel buddy on these errands.
没事
Sure.
可不是每天都有机会去泊机处放倒一帮武装分子
It's not every day you get to beat up a militia group in anchorage,
夺机飞往迈阿密的
then hop a plane to Miami.
你就开始  干这种活儿
So is this what you're doing from now on,
抓坏人了吗
you're chasing down bad guys?
应该不会
I doubt it.
太多工作要做
There's still too much work to be done.
什么工作
What kind of work?
准备
Preparation.
明白  我们马上离开
I understand. We're leaving now.
-该走了  -去哪儿
- Time to go. - Where to?
-圣路易斯  -好极了
- St. Louis. - Oh, great.
那里有家牛排店的菲力牛排爽过做爱
I know a steak joint that serves a filet that's better than sex.
听起来真美味  但你不能跟我同去了
Yummy as that sounds, you won't be joining me.
她需要你去别的地方
She needs you somewhere else.
哪儿
W-where?
你还是回去贩可卡因吧  小家伙
You should go back to dealing coke, Sonny.
比运炸药安全多了
It's a lot safer than moving explosives.
迈阿密
华盛顿特区
-你在吗  芬奇  -永远在  里瑟先生
- You there, Finch? - Always, Mr. Reese.
那边挺安静啊
Sounds rather quiet there.
我觉得麦考特唯一的危险
I think the only thing McCourt is in danger of
就是工作到太晚
is working too late.
恐怕你做他保镖的时间
I fear you may need to remain on his security detail
会比预期长
longer than anticipated.
我们是否该查看下真阿伯特特工如何了
Shouldn't we check in on the real Agent Abbott?
是啊  得有人帮他翻翻身
Yeah, I guess someone should turn him over.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
怎么回事
What's going on?
出事了  芬奇
Something's wrong, Finch.
抱歉
Sorry.
搞什么鬼  阿伯特
What the hell, Abbott?
不知道要敲门吗
You never heard of knocking?
抱歉  我以为是
I'm sorry. I thought I heard a...
算了
Never mind.
要我叫人吗
Should I call it in?
芬奇  麦考特和他的助手忙的
Finch, McCourt and his aide have been working
可不止是政策立场
on more than just policy positions.
也许他妻子是威胁
Might wanna consider his wife as a possible threat.
实际上  她的电邮显示她对于他的婚外情
Actually, her emails show that she's been aware of his affairs
已经知情很久了
for quite some time.
看来他们的婚姻更像是一份合同
Seems they have more of an arrangement than a marriage.
里瑟先生  我有发现了
Mr. Reese, I found something.
什么发现
What is it?
在弗斯科的帮助下  我追踪到
With Fusco's aid, I was able to trace
餐馆外那辆越野车的车牌
the license plate from the SUV outside the restaurant
属于一家租车公司
back to a rental car company.
似乎是被一家空壳公司租下的
It seems the vehicle was rented to a shell corporation
设立该空壳公司的是
set up by another company...
德西玛科技
Decima Technologies.
德西玛
Decima.
你说对了  芬奇  全都有联系
You were right, Finch. It's all connected.
麦考特肯定威胁到了"撒马利亚人"
McCourt must be a threat to Samaritan.
所以他们才会在这里
Which would explain why they're here.
杜兰
Duran.
有件事你得知道  警官
There's something you should know, Officer.
他不是特勤局的
He's not Secret Service.
什么  你是谁
What? Who's this?
这才是真阿伯特探员
Here's the real Agent Abbott.
别这样
Don't do it.
-阿伯特  你在干嘛  -待着别动
- Abbott, what are you doing? - Stay put.
里瑟先生  发生什么事了
Mr. Reese, what's happening?
计划有变  我抓住麦考特了
Change of plans. I've got McCourt.
抓住他了
Got him?
你绑架了美国国会议员
You've kidnapped a United States congressman?
如你所说  芬奇  如今形势古怪啊
Like you said, Finch, these are strange times.
你好啊  哈罗德
Hello, Harold.
里瑟先生  我必须请教下
Mr. Reese, I have to question the wisdom
绑架官员的意义何在
of abducting an elected official.
德西玛揭穿了我的身份  开了枪
Decima blew my cover and started shooting.
国会警察和特勤局
The Capitol Police and Secret Service
正满城搜捕你
are scouring the city for you now,
还有联调局和一堆各种局
plus the FBI and about a dozen other three-letter agencies.
看看他们干得如何
Let's see how they're doing.
独立大道向西
Traveling west on Independence Avenue.
议员被绑架到一辆黑色越野车中
Congressman was abducted in a black sport utility vehicle,
伊利诺伊州车牌
Illinois license plate ...
指我们
That's us.
那我们得弃车躲躲了
So we need to dump the car and hole up somewhere.
好吧  前面左拐  我知道一个地方
Very well. Turn left up here. I know a place.
美国牛肉咨询公司  芬奇
American Beef Consultants, Finch?
我们需要的是藏身  不是汉堡
We need a hiding place, not a burger.
上个月我买下了牛肉工业的游说机构
Last month I bought the beef industry's lobbying arm.
而且不要鄙视汉堡  很美味的
And don't knock the hamburgers. They're superb.
不怎么像安全屋啊
Doesn't look like much of a safe house.
就是要这效果  我清理了这一层
That's the idea-- I cleared out this floor
补充了一些顶级设备
and added a couple of cutting-edge amenities--
存粮充足  玻璃防弹
fully stocked kitchen, bulletproof glass.
好了  麦克
Okay, Mac.
你要尖叫吗
You gonna scream?
约翰
John.
要耐心细致
Bedside manner.
议员  说起来可能有点奇怪
Congressman, strange as it may seem,
我们不想伤害你  我们是来帮你的
we wish you no harm, we're here to help.
但是我们需要问你几个问题
But we do need to ask you a few questions,
希望你不要大喊求救
and we would prefer that you did not yell for assistance.
你们是谁
Who are you?
算是  安全顾问
Security advisors... of a sort.
好吧  我可以付赎金
Yeah, I can pay the ransom.
要多少钱我都可以给你们
I can get however much money you need.
有人要杀你
Someone's trying to kill you.
是啊  你们
Yeah, you.
什么  不  我们是保护你的
What? No. We're protection.
保护
Protection?
你装成  特勤局的
You posed as, uh, Secret Service,
打晕了我的保镖
you knock out my security detail,
然后用枪指着绑架了我
and then you abduct me at gunpoint.
其实我几天前还对你开枪来着
Technically I also shot at you a couple days ago.
快救命啊
Somebody help me, please!
够了
That's enough!
我们没时间了
We don't have time for this.
你想活命  就必须帮我们
If you wanna survive, you're gonna have to help us.
我同事把你从那个杀手分队手中救出来
Now, about that hit squad that my colleague rescued you from...
杀手分队  那才不是什么杀手分队
Hit squad? That wasn't a hit squad.
那是想把我从你手中救出的联调局
That was the FBI trying to save me from you.
我知道看起来是那样
I know it may have appeared that way,
但我保证真相并非如你所想
But I assure you that was not the case.
你知道一家叫德西玛科技的公司吗
What do you know about company called Decima?
从没听过  怎么了
Never heard of it. Why?
他们派了一队人马来杀你
They sent the team that tried to kill you.
你知道为什么他们会视你为敌吗
Do you know why they would consider you an enemy?
视我为敌
Me, an enemy?
我没树过敌  大家都喜欢我
I'm not an enemy. People love me.
我很久以前也许惹恼过一些人
I mean, I might piss a few people off along the way,
但我尽可能补偿他们了
but I always get 'em whatever it is they need.
我擅长做交易
I'm a deal maker.
你们有何目的
So what is it with you guys?
你们想要什么  钱吗
What do you want, money?
想要和总统通电话吗
You want a personal telephone call from the President?
我可以安排
'cause I can get it.
求你们了  拜托
Just please, come on.
放我走吧
Let me go.
不管你们要什么  我是你们的人
Then, whatever you need, I'm your man.
芬奇  趴下
Finch, get down!
-你们还好吗  -我们没事
- You guys all right? - Yes, we're fine.
为什么都乱开枪呢
Why is everybody shooting at everybody?
你向联邦探员开枪了
I mean, if you're shooting at Federal Agents...
联邦探员不会乱枪开路
Feds don't walk in scattering lead.
德西玛找到我们了  怎么回事
Decima found us. How?
麦考特没有手机可追踪
McCourt has no phone to follow.
这是追踪器
It's a tracker.
谁给你这个的
Do you know who gave you this?
不知道  我在一周前的募款会上收到的
No idea. It was given to me at a fund-raiser a week ago.
更多枪手随后就到了
More operatives will be arriving soon.
我们快走
We need to go.
我们要离开绕城高速  需要一辆新车
We should leave the beltway. We'll need a new car.
还是老车吧  打火更容易
Or an old one-- easier to hotwire.
带上麦考特
Take McCourt.
又是这家伙  跟小强似的
This guy again. He's like a cockroach.
似乎我们最后的逃生路线  也要没了
Sounds like our last escape route is about to disappear.
射这家伙好过射警察
I'm more comfortable shooting this guy than the cops.
需要搭车吗
You guys going my way?
议员被一名白人男子绑架
Congressman was abducted by a white male,
身高一米九  深色头发  穿西装
6'3", dark hair, in suit.
请注意  疑犯携有武器  极其危险
Be advised, suspect is armed and extremely dangerous.
车不错  肖
Nice car, Shaw.
你怎么知道我们在这儿的
So how'd you know we'd be there?
本来不知道  直到五分钟前
I didn't until five minutes ago.
根给我电话了
I got a call from Root.
你就是我们要救的人吗
So you're the one we're saving?
是啊  你是谁
Yeah. Who are you?
现在是跑路司机
Right now I'm the getaway driver.
天啊  情况越来越不妙了
Boy, this just gets worse.
振作点  麦克
Cheer up, Mac.
好歹没和那个想杀你的家伙一起躺后备箱
You could be in the trunk with the guy who wants to kill you.
我们不能往回走  太危险了
We can't go back. It's too dangerous.
我可以试试猛冲过路障
I could try blasting through the roadblock.
"猛冲"这个词
The term "blasting"
听着不甚稳妥  肖女士
does not inspire great confidence, Ms. Shaw.
呼吸点新鲜空气吧  我去带后备箱那家伙
Time to get some fresh air. I'll get the guy in the trunk.
走吧
Let's go.
活动活动腿脚吧
Time to stretch your legs.
安全
All clear.
车道上的报纸  信件堆成山
Newspapers in the driveway, mail piled up.
肯定度假去了
Must be on vacation.
希望他们多度一天假吧
Let's hope they decide to stay another night.
现在怎么办
What now?
问点问题
Some answers.
我不知道还要跟你说多少次
Look, I don't know how many times I have to tell you.
我没做过任何让人想杀我的事情
I haven't done anything to make anybody wanna kill me.
在我们确认
Until we determine the reason
德西玛追杀你的原因之前
that Decima keeps making attempts on your life,
你必须跟我们待一起
you'll have to stay with us.
拿到德西玛那人的手机了吗
You have our Decima friend's phone?
我把手机卡拆了
I pulled out the sim card.
如果你们真的想保护我
If you really wanna protect me,
为什么不把我交给警察
why don't you just take me to the cops?
执法部门无法阻止
Law enforcement is no deterrent
那些追杀你的人  议员先生
to the people coming after you, Congressman.
这真是疯了
This is insane.
你肯定做了什么吸引他们注意的事
You've obviously done something to attract their attention.
比如呢
Like what?
德西玛是一家私人情报公司
Decima is a private intelligence company
在研发大规模监控项目
developing a large-scale surveillance program--
就是你公开反对的那种
the type of program that you've been vocally against.
一半国会议员都反对  然后呢
Along with half the congress. So?
但你在规则委员会的位置
But your position on the Rules Committee
令你有权力修改或叫停法案
gives you the power to alter or halt legislation.
你阻止过会影响德西玛计划的法案吗
Have you sidelined anything that would affect Decima's plans?
没有
No.
我不知道那家公司
I don't know anything about that company
不知道他们为什么追杀我
or why they would wanna kill me.
这是误会  天大的误会
This is all mistake, just a huge mistake.
毫无进展
We're not getting anywhere here.
或许肖运气会好点
Maybe Shaw's having some luck.
要么开口  要么流血致死
You can talk or bleed out.
你帮我  我们就帮你
You help us, we'll help you.
随你高兴  硬汉
Suit yourself, Tough Guy.
希望值得你送命
Hope it's worth dying for.
可能没必要了
That may not be necessary.
我通过短信加密中的一个关键薄弱点
I was able to get into his phone through a key vulnerability
黑进了他手机
in the sms encryption.
我想我们之前误解情况了
I think we may have misread this situation.
行动目标  保护
保护
"Protect"?
看来不止我们在乎
Seems we're not the only ones concerned
这位议员的安全
with the Congressman's safety.
那你是要保护麦考特不受谁的伤害
So who are you supposed to be protecting McCourt from?
我不知情
I wasn't given that information.
但在我们监视他的那一周里
But in the week we've been watching him,
唯一冲他开枪的人是你
the only ones who have taken a shot at him are you.
我能来杯咖啡吗
You think maybe I could get a coffee?
水也行啊
Or some water would be fine.
麦考特先生  你确定你不知道德西玛
Mr. McCourt, you're sure you have no knowledge of Decima?
我已经说过了
I already answered that.
干嘛还一直问
Why do you keep beating that drum?
因为他们是在保护你
Because they're protecting you.
保护我
Protecting me?
你刚还跟我说他们是来杀我
A minute ago you said they were trying to kill me.
没错
I did.
但那说不通
Something doesn't add up.
实际上  我想能说通
Actually I think it might.
我今天查阅了你的收入情况  议员
I looked into your finances earlier today, Congressman.
你做了什么
You did what?
我注意到你投资的股票  去年涨了20%
I noticed your stock portfolio, up 20% over last year.
你想说什么
What are you getting at?
你的交易活动
Your trading activities.
你的投资涨了20%
Your portfolio is up 20%
完全是因为你上两周的交易
due to trades you've made in the last two weeks.
这些交易的增值速度剧增六倍
Trades that have increased in value by over 600%.
所以呢
So?
所以
So...
要么你是全华盛顿最英明的投资人
either you're the smartest investor in Washington,
要么你收到了绝好的消息
or you're getting some very good information.
内部消息
Inside information.
我不喜欢你的含沙射影
I don't like what you're implying.
这不止是含沙射影了  议员
It's more than an implication, Congressman,
我要打电话给我认识的证监会调查员
And it'll become a call to an S.E.C. investigator I know
除非你对我们说实话
unless you're more truthful with us.
好吧
Okay.
我知道德西玛科技
I know Decima Technologies.
但他们不是要杀我
But they're not trying to kill me.
我们有共识
We have an understanding.
什么共识
What kind of an understanding?
他们需要一点小小的法案支持
They were looking for a little legislative support
他们的新监控项目
for their new surveillance program.
支持
Support?
你一直在主导指责政府监控
You've been leading the charge against government surveillance.
当然了
Course I have.
因为我知道政府无法保守秘密
'Cause I realized that the government can't keep a secret.
看看"棱镜"和"北极光"这些烂摊子
You look at, uh, Prism and this Northern Lights mess.
关于德西玛的项目你都知道什么
What do you know about Decima's program?
不多
Not much really.
只知道是个政府运行系统的替代品
Just that it's an alternative to a government-run system.
现在说来  这是皆大欢喜的事儿
Which, at this point, should make everybody happy.
作为回报
And in return for your support,
你得到股票内幕
You're getting insider stock tips.
你们是对聪明人  是吧
You're a couple of smart guys, you know?
当然你们理解
Surely you understand
在华盛顿  一切都是交易
that everything that happens in Washington is a deal.
而你擅长做交易
And you're a deal maker.
你要是不知道
In case you didn't know,
政府业务其实就是业务/生意
the business of governments is business.
他们在这区挨家挨户排查
They're moving grid to grid through the neighborhood.
我们得采取行动了
We need to make a move.
格里尔在安排"撒马利亚人"取代机器
Greer is positioning Samaritan to replace the machine.
麦考特在帮德西玛
McCourt is helping Decima.
我们一直当他是受害人
We've been looking at him as a victim,
但他其实是行凶者
but he's really a perpetrator.
我不确定
I'm not so sure.
他接触并不深
His involvement is tangential at best,
不了解格里尔的意图
and he doesn't know Greer's intentions.
如果他既非受害人又非行凶者
But if he's not a victim or a perp,
为什么机器会给出他的号码
Then why did the machine give us his number?
我们到底是要阻止什么
What is it we're supposed to be stopping?
我不确定我们是要阻止什么
I'm not sure we're supposed to be stopping anything.
芬奇  你说过麦考特可以加快或叫停法案
Finch, you said McCourt could speed up or halt legislation.
是的  他的特殊职位可以移除
Yes, he's in a unique position to remove
"撒马利亚人"的立法障碍
any legislative roadblock to Samaritan.
所以没有麦考特
So without McCourt,
"撒马利亚人"就不能被国会通过
Samaritan doesn't get past Congress.
格里尔就没法获取国安局的监控信号
And Greer wouldn't get access to the NSAs surveillance feeds.
所以机器会给出他的号码
Then that's why we got his number.
他是受害人
He is the victim.
他有生命危险
His life is in danger.
谁要杀他
But from who?
我们
Us.
机器想要让我们杀掉麦考特
I think the machine wants us to kill McCourt.
约翰  想想你在说什么
John, think about what you're saying.
想过了
I have.
德西玛不杀麦考特
Just because Decima is not the threat to McCourt
不意味着我们就得杀
doesn't mean that we must be.
机器被设计来挽救生命  不是夺取生命
The machine is designed to save lives, not take them.
那它会吗
But could it?
机器会让我们杀人吗
Could the machine ever tell us to kill someone?
有可能吗
Is it possible?
有此可能性
It's conceivable.
要在多糟糕的情况下
How bad would the situation have to be?
非常糟糕
Bad.
它必面是看出了个体的行为
It would have to see that an individual's actions
会直接造成他人丧生
could directly result in the loss of others' lives.
多少人丧生  十几  上百  多少
How many lives? A dozen, a hundred? How many?
很多  我不确定
A lot. I'm not sure.
我没想过事情会发展到这个地步
I never dreamt it would come to this.
已经如此了
It has.
你的机器  知道要出事了
Your machine-- it sees something coming--
大事  它想让我们阻止
Something bad-- and it wants us to stop it.
我不知道  你也不知道
I don't know. You don't know that.
我从没真正信任过你的机器
Look, I've never entirely trusted your machine,
但它是你造的  我信任你
but you built it, and I trust you.
是你说我们不能低估
You're the one who said we can't underestimate
"撒马利亚人"的威胁
the threat of Samaritan.
麦考特先生
Mr. McCourt,
你得取消你和德西玛的交易
You have to call off your deal with Decima.
他们的监控项目  不能被批准
Their surveillance program cannot be approved.
你什么人  隐私激进疯子吗
What--what are you, one of those privacy nut jobs?
是因为这个吗
Is that what this is about?
有了政府监控信号
With access to the government's surveillance feeds,
德西玛就能随心所欲  获取任何信息
Decima will be able to acquire any information,
任何秘密
any secret it desires,
然后出售  价高者得
and sell it to the highest bidder.
这肯定就是美国政府
And that would be the United States government.
也许目前是
Perhaps, for now.
但是  不受限制的权限会造成
But unbridled access will create
失控的信息滥用
unlimited opportunities for abuse.
人们会受伤  会送命
People will be ruined, lives will be lost.
结果将会是灾难性的
The results will be nothing short of catastrophic.
那些项目总是会引起争议
These programs are always gonna be controversial
但却不可或缺
but also inevitable.
一曝光人们就会大动肝火
People get up in arms whenever they go public,
但最终都会平息
but eventually the noise dies down,
因为事实是  人们想被保护
because the simple truth is that people wanna be protected.
他们只是不想知道自己是怎么被保护
They just don't wanna know how.
是我还没有开价
Maybe I haven't offered you the right incentive.
要多少钱
So how much?
你说什么
Excuse me?
放弃支持德西玛的项目  要多少钱
To withdraw your support for Decima's program, how much?
我这么做是为了保护国家安全
You know, I did this to keep the country safe.
的确  此一过程中我自己捞了点好处
And yeah, maybe I got a little something for myself during the process.
那只是说明我胜任自己的工作啊
All that makes me is good at what I do.
我不会取消交易
I'm not calling off the deal.
有人来了  特战队  联邦特工  大阵仗
Looks like we've got company-- S.W.A.T., Feds, the works.
里瑟先生  我从不想要
Mr. Reese, it was never my intention
有人因为机器被杀
for people to be killed because of the machine.
你以为它把恐怖份子的号码告诉政府后
What do you think happened when it gave the government
会发生什么
a terrorist number?
你以为我们以前是做什么工作的
What do you think we used to do for a living?
但那个人不是恐怖分子
That man is not a terrorist.
他只是投机取巧的腐败棋子
He's just an opportunistic and corrupt pawn.
他造成的威胁只多不少
That doesn't make the threat any less real.
我们不是刺客  我们保护人
We are not assassins. We protect people.
这不就是吗
Isn't that what we're doing,
牺牲一个生命  拯救无数生命
sacrificing the life of one to save the lives of many?
肖  帮腔啊
Shaw, help me out here.
要在六个月前  我早把那男的一枪爆头了
Six months ago, I would've already put a bullet in that guy's head.
不过自从开始跟你们混
But ever since hanging around you guys,
我有点习惯救人了
I've kind of gotten used to saving people.
但这一切都基于对机器的信任
But we've only been able to do that by trusting the machine.
要是机器说这个人得死
And if it's saying that this guy's gotta go,
我觉得我们应该信任它
I think we should still trust it.
约翰  我求你想想动手的后果
John, I urge you to consider the consequences of this action.
想想不动手的后果
There are consequences to not acting.
比如西蒙斯  和乔丝
Like with Simmons and Joss.
别这样
Don't do this.
我们让他走出门  德西玛就赢了
If we let him walk out that door, Decima wins.
"撒马利亚人"就会上线
Samaritan will go live.
那只是可能  并不一定
It's a possibility but not a certainty.
也许还有其他办法  我们从没遇到过这种情况
There may be another way. We've never been here.
但你真的愿意冒这个险吗
But are you really willing to take that risk?
哈罗德
Harold?
我们从一开始走到现在  很多事都变了
Since we started this, things have changed.
我们也变了
We've changed.
但我们的使命  我们的目的  始终如一
But the mission, our purpose, has always been constant--
拯救生命
to save lives.
如果这一点也变了  如果我们沦落到
If that's changed somehow, if we're in a place now
机器要我们谋杀的地步
where the machine is asking us to commit murder...
我撑不下去了
That's a place I can't go.
我可能要放弃了
I'm afraid this is where I get off.
约翰
John.
再次捡起
Pick it up, pick it all up
重新开始
And start again
再一次  回家
You've got a second chance You could go home
逃开一切
Escape it all
无关紧要
It's just irrelevant
心溢温柔
You've got a warm heart
才思泉涌
You've got a beautiful brain
瞬间分崩
But it's disintegrating
不过黄粱一梦
It's just medicine
来时路  犹可回
You could still be what you want to
人生只如初见
What you said you were when I met you
我给你机会考虑我的提议了
You've had an opportunity to consider my proposal.
要帮我们吗
Will you help us?
我和我的同事们都很乐意
My colleagues and I would like to,
但可惜现在时机尚不成熟
but unfortunately now is not the time.
也许先展示一下系统的能力
Perhaps a demonstration of my system's capabilities
可以说服你  你的国家等不起了
will convince you that your country cannot afford to wait.
在限定的区域测试一下  比如
Test in a limited area, say...
纽约市
New York City.
就24小时  干净利落
24 hours, quick, clean.
然后就关闭
Then we shut it down.
不动枪  不动警察  只要信息
No guns, no police, just information.
什么信息
What kind of information?
只要国安局给我们提供
If the NSA provides us
纽约市的监控摄像信号
with New York City's surveillance feeds,
我们就给你找出一名恐怖分子
we will find you a terrorist.
你找出一千名恐怖分子都行
You could find me a thousand terrorists,
但我说过了
but like I said,
国会通不过的
we'll never get this through congress.
我也告诉你了  反对声不是问题
And as I told you, dissenting voices would not be a problem.
人生只如初见
What you said you were when I met you
来时路  犹可回
You could still be what you want to
人生只如初见
What you said you were
如我初见你
When I met you
如你初见我
When you met me
如我初见你
When I met you
该移去障碍了
It's time to remove those obstacles.
接电话吧  参议员
Answer your phone, Senator.
你好吗  加里森
How you doing, Garrison?
我是罗杰・麦考特
This is Roger McCourt.
我听说你正准备向国会递交份法案
I understand you'll be preparing some legislation.
是吗
Is that right?
只要你搞定参议院
If you can handle the Senate,
我保证众议院规则委员会帮忙通过
I can ensure that the House Rules facilitate a quiet passage.
你能做到
You can do all that?
当然  参议员
Absolutely, Senator.
好  那就
Okay. Let's...
做吧
do it.
好极了
Excellent.
有任何需要  尽管开口
Now if there's anything else you need, just ask.
我是你们的人
I'm your man.
只得黄粱一梦
From all the medicine
黄粱一梦
Medicine
来时路  犹可回
You could still be what you want to be
人生只如初见
What you said you were when you met me
来时路  犹可回
You could still be what you want to
维吉尔
Virgil,
可以运行了吗
are we operational?
正好赶上剪彩
You're just in time for the ribbon cutting.
监控信号正在上线
Feeds are coming online now.
启动试运行
Commencing beta test.
如你我初见
When I met you
连接已建立
好了  我们有24小时
Okay, we have 24 hours.
很好
Splendid.
输入目标
给我找出  哈罗德・芬奇
Find me Harold Finch.
哈罗德・芬奇
搜寻  哈罗德・芬奇
载入数据